https://www.stalbans.anglican.org/diocese/privacy-policy/#cookies

Privacy and Cookies Policy Notice
This policy notice summarises how the St Albans Diocesan Board of Finance (SADBF), as Data Controller, uses and protects any personal information that is collected or is provided to the SADBF by you as the Data Subject, for the purposes of undertaking diocesan duties supporting the mission and ministry of the Church of England. A more detailed policy description can be found in the Data Privacy Policy.
The SADBF is committed to ensuring that data subjects’ privacy is protected. If a data subject is asked to provide information by which they can be identified, when holding a position within the Diocese or using this website, they can be assured it will only be used in accordance with this privacy notice.
The SADBF may change this policy notice from time to time by updating this page. Data subjects should check this page and the Data Privacy Policy to ensure that data subjects are happy with any changes.
Personal information
Contact details and information about posts that people hold, which appear in the Online Directory, are provided directly from the Diocesan database, which is maintained through the parish annual return process, the database portal and the normal business processes of the SADBF.
These contact details may, depending upon the role/posts that are held, be used to maintain contact with the parishes by distributing information on events and activities and when requesting statistical and financial information relating to the parish or church the data subject is connected to.
The Online Directory exists to help enquirers contact their local church and also for clergy and parish officers to easily contact their counterparts around the Diocese. However, data in the Diocesan database relating to schools is not displayed in the Online Directory and only school headteachers names and general school contact details are published in the Diocesan printed directory.
Any personal details submitted through the events or jobs sections of this site are used only for the purposes of administration of those activities or adverts.
Controlling data subject’s personal information
The SADBF will not sell, distribute or lease data subject’s personal information to third parties unless we are required to do so by law.
It may be shared within the structures of the Church of England and other ecumenical partners within the Diocese and nationally.
This data may be published in the publicly available Diocesan Directory and Website with consent. In this case the data subject will be contacted and sent a link to a website page where they will be asked for their consent and for them to control which part/s of their data is made publicly visible.
Data subjects may, under the GDPR and Data Protection Act 2018, request details of personal information which the SADBF holds about them. If a data subject should require a copy of this information they should contact the Data Protection Officer, or for clergy, the Diocesan Bishop’s office.
If a data subject believes that any information that the SADBF is holding is incorrect or incomplete, or wishes to change the use of their personal information, they can request a change at any time by emailing the Database Administrator.
If a data subject believes that the SADBF have not managed their information correctly, the data subject may make a complaint to the Information Commissioner’s Office (ICO) at https://ico.org.uk/.
The SADBF keeps data subjects’ personal data secure within EU data centres. It is encrypted and securely held with access granted only to those that have an operational or Diocesan business need to do so.
What the Diocese collects
The SADBF collects anonymised data from visits to this website for analytical purposes via our use of cookies as explained below. If a data subject holds a position within the Diocese or registers with the SADBF we will collect some or all of the following information:
Name
Position/role
Address/es
Telephone number/s
Email address/es
Gender
What the Diocese does with the information we gather
The SADBF requires the information gathered to ensure that the data submitted via forms, correctly identifies the data subject as having permission to upload the data they may be submitting. The information is used to maintain correspondence between Parishes, Deaneries, the Bishops offices and the Diocesan office for the purposes of conducting normal business processes. The information may also be used for the following reasons:
Internal record keeping
To improve our website
How long does the Diocese keep the information?
Personal information is kept within the database whilst a person is in a position within a Parish or the Diocese. It will then be deleted, unless required for record keeping.
E-News
Subscribers to E-News should read the E-News privacy policy.
Security
The SADBF is committed to ensuring that data subject information is secure. In order to prevent unauthorized access or disclosure, we have put in place suitable physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information collected online.
How cookies are used on this website
Cookies are small text files that are placed on your computer by websites that you visit. They are widely used by websites in order to make websites work, or work more efficiently, as well as to provide information to the owners of the site. The table below explains the cookies we use and why.
ServiceCookieDescription
Content Management Systemcomment*
PHPSESSID
wordpress*
wp*To identify your unique session on the website. Used to maintain the integrity of your session while transacting information with a website (accessing secure areas, forms submissions etc).
Cookie PreferenceCookieControlThis cookie is used to remember a user's choice about cookies on this website. Where users have previously indicated a preference, that user's preference will be stored in this cookie.
Formidable Forms Profrm_formAllows you to re-access your registered account profile during a web session.
Google Analyticscollect
_ga
_gat
_gid
_utma
_utmzThese cookies are used to collect information about how visitors use our website. We use the information to compile reports and to help us improve the website. The cookies collect information in a way that does not directly identify anyone, including the number of visitors to the website and blog, where visitors have come to the website from and the pages they visited.
Read Google's overview of privacy and safeguarding data .
Google
- Custom Search
- Maps
- reCAPTCHA1P_JAR
CONSENT
NID
APISID
DV
HSID
OGP
PREF
SID
SNIDSets a unique ID to remember your preferences and other information such as website statistics and track conversion rates.
Read more about the types of cookies used by Google
Print Friendlyprintfriendly-font-classThis is used for printing to remember the selected font.
Third-Party Cookieseg.
fr (Facebook)
sc_anonymous_id (Soundcloud)We embed media content from providers such as Facebook, Flickr, Soundcloud, Vimeo (see below) and YouTube (see below). By doing so media content providers use cookies from their own sites (called third-party cookies) to make their content display and to collect information about usage. We have made every effort to limit third-party cookies to be necessary only, such as using YouTube's privacy-enhanced mode, but there might be other tracking and marketing cookies they use that we are unaware of. Please refer to the media content provider's own cookie policies for more details of the cookies they use for their embedded content.
You can also disable third-party cookies in your internet browser but it may affect embedded content displayed on our website. Visit www.cookiesandyou.com/disable-cookies
for instructions on how to do this.
Vimeoplayer
vuidWe embed videos from our official Vimeo channel. When you press play Vimeo will drop third party cookies to enable the the video to play and to collect analytics data such as how long a viewer has watched the video. These cookies do not track individuals.
YouTubeGPS
PREF
remote_sid
VISITOR_INFO1_LIVE
VSCWe embed videos from our official YouTube channel using YouTube’s privacy-enhanced mode. This mode may set cookies on your computer once you click on the YouTube video player, but YouTube will not store personally-identifiable cookie information for playbacks of embedded videos using the privacy-enhanced mode.
Read more at YouTube’s embedding videos information page.
Links to other websites
The SADBF website may contain links to enable visitors to easily visit other websites of interest. These links are there to provide a means of access to certain other sites and their use means that the visitor leaves the SADBF website. The Diocese does not have any control over these other websites to which links are provided. The Diocese therefore cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information provided by a visitor whilst visiting such sites, and such sites are not governed by this privacy notice.
Visitors should exercise caution and look at the privacy notice applicable to the website in question.
